I sit here and I can 't believe that it happened .
And yet I have to believe it .
Dreams or nightmares .
Madness or sanity ,
I don 't know which is which .
I 'll just take a minute !
Don 't worry , the farm will be great for her .
Apartment was beginning to scare me , too .
For the first time in months , I 'm free .
Forget the doctors .
Forget that place .
I 'm okay now .
We 'll start over .
Hey , Jess ! Come on , we gotta get moving !
Don 't tell them , act normal .
Find anything good ?
It 's great .
What 's it say ?
" Frail as the leaves that shiver on a spray .
" Like them we flourish ,
" like them , decay . "
See ?
You 're less frightened already .
Cast off !
What have we got in the case ?
My mother-in-law .
I wished it was mine . Where you folks going ?
Other side of Brookfield .
It 's a farm on Cove Road called the Old Bishop Place .
Do you know it ?
Yes , I do .
Well , we 'll be on the other side very soon .
This is your new hometown , Jessica .
Was that it ? Wait , wait ! Can we go around again ?
Okay . Waltz us around again , Woody . Don 't blink or you 're gonna miss it .
- Look what they 're driving . - Damn hippies .
Creeps .
Some welcoming committee .
I think maybe it 's our mode of transportation .
Look at those bandages . I think these guys are left over from the Civil War .
It 's cheaper than a station wagon .
Good riddance .
Oh , God , it 's fantastic !
The ...
I 'm so excited .
The stuff for supper is on top
and the bedding and the sheets like that are all in the very front .
Woman 's work is never done .
Jessica , why have you come here ?
Get it open ?
You okay ?
Don 't tell them . They won 't believe you .
Yes .
Well , let 's go in .
Do you like it ?
What 's wrong ?
It 's okay , Jess . I saw it , too .
- What 's the matter ? - Someone 's upstairs .
No kidding ? That 's great , eh ?
Stay here .
I really did see something .
I believe you .
We know you 're in here , now come out .
That 's the girl !
Hold it !
What are you doing here ?
I mean , I 'm sorry if we frightened you but you just scared the hell out of us .
Oh , that 's all right .
Who are you ?
This place belongs to me now .
I just found this place and I thought it was abandoned , so I just
sort of moved in .
Then I saw this hearse coming up the drive .
We must 've scared you as much as you scared us .
Well , I 'll get my things .
And let 's get the rest of the stuff , Woody .
- Woody ? - Yeah , yeah .
- Is this your room ? - Yes .
I mean no .
Where will you go ?
Town ?
Sounds good enough for me .
You don 't care where you go ?
Do you ?
Well ...
Yes . I think I do now .
Have you any transportation ?
Well , how will you get to town ? It 's a couple of miles , isn 't it ?
Look , why don 't you stay and have dinner with us and spend the night ?
Oh , thanks . I guess I 'll keep moving .
Please do . We have plenty and we can drive you into town in the morning .
Please .
Stay .
Well , why not ?
Good .
I 'm Jessica .
Hi . I 'm Emily .
- That 's far enough . - It better be .
That 's great .
You go to school ?
I went and then I dropped .
Then I went again .
And if I like it around here , I plan to drop again .
I probably should go back to school but I don 't know why .
What do I need a degree for ?
But don 't you live somewhere ?
Oh yeah , sure , but ...
I haven 't been there for a long time
and I 'm not sure I 'm ready to go back yet .
Nice .
Do you play ?
No . I can 't even carry a tune .
Stay forever
My love
We 're together
Leave the world
You know about
And stay with me
My love
Stay forever
We 're together
My love
He likes her .
Leave the world
You know about
It 's blood , Jessica , it 's blood .
It 's blood .
Blood , blood .
Wow !
He 's terrific !
I mean , really .
He 's an important man . He was with the Philharmonic .
Are you gonna play somewhere around here ?
No , he 's gonna farm , raise apples ,
have a garden , get back to nature .
He 's a nut .
I 'm the nut .
Coffee is being served in our living room .
Great to have a fire .
Didn 't you have a fireplace in New York ?
New York ? Have you ever been to New York ?
No . I 've always wanted to go there .
- Oh ? - Yeah .
- It 's a mad city . - Gosh , it 's ...
How long have you been here ?
Ages .
Did you ever get lonely ?
Oh , sure . Sure .
But
sometimes it 's not lonely .
Sometimes
I hear things .
Like , you know , when I 'm alone and it 's very quiet , like now .
You can let your imagination go
and listen to the stillness
and watch it get dark ,
and the shadows come to life .
You know what I mean ?
Have you ever had anything like that happen to you ?
Well ...
Yes .
Like , like what ?
Like ...
Once , I was going to your concert and I was afraid I was gonna be late ,
and I was very exhausted around that time
because my father had just passed away .
And
I woke up ,
and suddenly I saw my father .
And I heard his voice . He was calling to me .
" Jessica . "
It was probably me begging for her to be on time .
For a change .
Let 's have a séance .
Why not ? Don 't you believe in spirits ?
Nothing 's ever completely dead .
Right . I even hear the Twist is coming back .
I 'm calling on the spirits of everyone who ever died in this house .
If you 're present , give us a sign .
Give us a sign .
All the dead , come to us .
Me ? Oh , I can 't .
Call them .
I 'm calling on all the spirits of everyone who 's ever died in this house .
Give us a sign .
I 'm here , Jessica .
Jessica , I 'm here .
Come to us .
A toast to my bride , Abigail ,
and to all the Bishops .
Abigail .
My Abigail .
Oh , God , it 's sad .
We gave a séance and nobody came .
- I guess we 'll say good night . - All right .
- Good night , Woody , old pal . - Good night .
- Good night , kids . - Good night .
Gee , that really , you know , got to me .
" Sacred to the memory of Venture Smith , an African .
" Though the son of a king ,
" he was kidnapped and sold as a slave .
" But by his industry ,
" he acquired money to purchase his freedom . "
That 's our motto , that 's like us .
" Died , September 10th , 1805 ,
" in the 77th year of his life . "
Venture .
Oh , aren 't they beautiful ?
In memory of ...
Anyway , who 's left to remember them ?
Angel faces .
They look so merciless .
Hey , honey , come on .
Jess , come on .
You really believe in that kind of stuff ?
I don 't know .
You believe in that kind of stuff ?
What 's the matter ?
I guess
it 's just been a long time .
And I don 't know you yet .
Things like that .
Take me for a walk .
Your friend Jessica seems
- unhappy . - No .
No , no , she 's okay .
She was away for six months .
Got back a couple of weeks ago , better .
What 's the matter ?
Nothing .
You 're very beautiful .
Thank you .
I guess we 've all moved around ,
we 're all running from something .
That 's why they have this place .
Duncan blew his savings for it . He 's broke now .
We 're going to have to sell some stuff to get money to live on .
Are you going to live here , too ?
I don 't know yet . They asked me to .
I 'll stick around and help Dunc get started with the work in the orchard .
Then who knows ? I 'll probably move on .
We 're all kind of
wandering spirits , you know ?
I guess so .
Don 't be in such a hurry .
Don 't worry ,
I won 't go away .
I 'm coming to get you ! I 'm coming to get you !
Give me some soap .
- Okay ? - Yeah .
Do my back .
There you go , ma 'am .
Great !
This is great !
- One scrub girl needed immediately . - This is my ancient Finnish method .
Oh , good ! Oh , that feels good .
Okay , let 's switch .
Isn 't this the life ?
Don 't you feel happy ?
That 's nice .
Oh , that feels great .
Okay , I 'm finished .
- Where to ? - I 'll go fix lunch .
Oh , no . Wait , I 'll do it .
No , no , stay , swim . I have to pack anyway .
Okay , thanks .
Well , I 'm going in for another little swim .
- Wanna come ? Anybody wanna come ? - You swim , we 'll watch .
Lazy .
Jessica .
Come to me .
Dunc !
Oh , God !
Jess , what 's the matter ?
Out there . In the water .
- I was swimming in the cove . - It 's okay , it 's all right .
There was this thing . And it touched me .
Thing ? What thing ?
I don 't know , but it was white .
It was kind of awful , like a kind of shark .
- Jessica ... - Believe me , please .
That 's nonsense . Jessica , there is nothing in this cove .
Look !
- No , no , no . - Well , look at it .
We 'll get you dry . We 'll get you dry .
Jess , look ! Look ! There 's nothing here !
Now he thinks I 'm getting sick again . But I 'm not .
Liar , liar . Liar , liar .
Well , if we hope to find anything around this place
that we can sell in town , we 'd better start looking for it .
No money , no food .
So let 's go .
It 's you .
Are you ready ?
Can 't we keep this , Duncan ?
Put it in .
You 're going to sell this ?
- Yeah . - We hope so .
But they 're people . They have history .
You can 't just sell them like an old car .
People who sell old cars . Let 's go , Jessica .
Okay .
Hop in , Emily .
I thought you said
you wouldn 't go away .
Did you believe me ?
Yes .
Yes , I did .
- Let 's ask her to stay . - You want to ?
All right .
On behalf of the Board of Directors , we 'd like to ask you to stay .
I 'll unpack your stuff .
Thank you .
Glad to have you .
I won 't go away , Jessica .
I 'll never go away .
Do you find her attractive ?
Who ? Emily ?
Right .
Yeah .
Hello ?
Can you sell me some eggs ?
Come on down here and get them .
I 'm looking for some place to sell antiques , like lamps and a table .
If there was a place , I sure wouldn 't tell you .
Do you mind ?
Hey , watch it !
What happened ?
They probably get back in their cages after dark .
What a bunch of weirdoes .
Duncan , why are they all bandaged ?
You know , the chicken farmer had something , too .
On his neck .
- Hello . - Hello .
Anything special you 're looking for ? I 'm Sam Dorker .
- Hi . - Sam .
Hi , Sam . I 'm Duncan . This is my wife , Jessica .
- Glad to see you . - Hello .
- Are you passing through ? - No , we just moved here .
We 're new in town .
More refugees from urban blight , eh ?
I had a shop up until two years ago in New York on Second Avenue .
Where ?
Oh , between 52nd and 53rd .
We lived on 49th and 3rd .
- Oh , really ? - They tore the building down and ...
Well , I just couldn 't take it .
They built a pizza parlor next door to me .
I just couldn 't stand the smell .
But I love it up here . The air is fresh and clean .
- Oh , yeah . - And the fishing is just great .
The man who owned the shop before me lived to be 96
so I expect to be here for some time .
Well , what can I show you ?
I 've got a marvelous old
grandfather clock here , if you 've got room for it .
It 's a real steal at $ 375 .
I 'll steal it !
And at the other end of the scale ...
Oh , you like that . I was just about to show you that . That 's a male fiori lamp .
- Do you understand Italian ? - No .
Male fiori , that means flowers of evil .
Or evil flowers .
And they got it painted right on there .
Now , right up here I 've got some marvelous old things ,
real early Americana .
Got a marvelous , old deacon 's bench up here .
It 'll seat eight in a pinch .
That 's a joke .
Mr. Dorker , we 're really not interested in buying , we 're selling .
Oh , well , lead on , MacDuncan .
- What 've you got ? - Well , sir , I 've got a couple of nice jugs ,
and a chair and a table .
And some bottles , a couple lamps , real nice silver frame .
Bridle , some other stuff .
Flowers of evil .
How can anything this pretty be evil ?
It 's just old , that 's all .
When we have money again ,
this is the kind of stuff we 're gonna buy for the house .
That 's some very nice stuff .
Some of it . Some of it .
What about this ? It 's silver .
Yes , I guess so .
Very nice . Very nice piece .
But I ...
What ?
The Bishops . There 's no mistaking the Bishops .
Well , we bought the old Bishop place .
- Who 'd you deal with , old Harold ? - No , Harold 's gone to Florida .
It was an agent that showed me the place . Why ?
He tell you the stories about Abigail Bishop drowning ?
1880 , and all that ? It 's quite a story .
Sam , how much do you think this stuff 's worth to you ?
Well , I ... Let 's see .
I can give you $ 150 for it .
And $ 50 more for this .
$ 200 ?
But even some of the little jewelry costs more
and you said they were very nice pieces .
Well , frankly , I feel very funny about buying them .
I think I 'll have some trouble trying to sell them around here .
But think what you could get for them in New York , Mr. Dorker .
Duncan , couldn 't we keep this ?
$ 250 is the best I can do .
Well , all right . Come on , we 'll take it .
You know the story about the Bishops is really extraordinary .
Yeah .
Abigail never got to wear that wedding dress ...
Mr. Dorker .
She drowned in the cove behind her house .
Your house , I mean .
Never found her body . The legend is that she 's still alive .
Some say she 's a vampire
and roams the countryside .
Mr. Dorker , we 're sort of in a hurry . Could we have the money ?
Of course .
That was very rude , cutting him off . Don 't do it again .
You 're making me sick by worrying about me so much .
We won 't be long . I 'll make dinner .
Hi , Woody !
Oh gosh , it 's so beautiful . Can we really stay ?
We 'll try .
Hey , don 't touch that . It 's poison .
- What is it ? - It 's a mole .
It has no eyes ?
Duncan , get a container so we can keep it , please .
Okay . I 'll get a box from the house
- and I 'll come back for you . - Okay .
I 'll be all right . Just hurry before it gets away .
Okay .
It was the antique dealer . Dead , right here .
I swear it , I saw it .
Duncan , it 's true .
He was lying right here .
And there was blood !
I know what you think of me but I swear it 's true .
And there was a girl .
I 'm scared . Is it happening again ?
Duncan , that 's her !
Here , who are you ?
- Why did you run ? - You see ?
Tell him , tell him you led me to the body .
Tell him . Who are you ?
Why have you been following me ? What do you want ?
Don 't push her , Jess . Give her a chance .
I 'm not going to hurt you .
Did you see a body ? Did you ?
Tell me what you want .
Did you see a body ?
What ?
You can 't speak ?
What 's that ?
She led me to the body .
- What 's the matter with her ? - She knows who killed that man .
What man ?
I don 't know .
Did you see anybody ?
Did you see someone attack somebody ? Attack ? Attack .
Did you see anybody ? Did you ?
For God 's sake , Jessica , leave her alone .
You still don 't believe me .
You don 't believe there 's anything strange going on .
I think it 's ...
- It 's all strange . - You think I 'm crazy ?
Admit it .
Who 's that ?
There was this enormous cake that was terrorizing England .
Angel 's food or devil 's food ?
Devil 's food cake .
And it would ooze into the windows and into the doors
and engulf the people . It 'd eat everything in its way .
It was traveling down the coast from Scotland .
Whenever it would come to a town or a village , it would call out .
" Here comes the cake .
BBC sent out ...
He wants her .
He 'll never believe me again . No one will .
Did it happen ?
... little old lady ...
... and she 's got her ear to the ...
Come , Jessica . Come with me , Jessica .
" Who 's there ? Who 's there ? "
And a voice comes back ,
" It 's not the cake ! "
Duncan 's mine now .
You think he loves you ?
He 's mine now .
I 'm just ... I 'm kind of a little tired .
Think I 'll say good night .
- Good night , everybody . - Good night .
Good night , Jess .
The mole 's sleepy .
Well , I 'm very tired . I think I 'll go up .
- Good night . - Good night .
Take care of your wife , there .
Good night .
You sleeping ?
You know the name of that big tree out in the yard ?
Jessica .
That 's a maple . I know how to tell a sugar maple .
How ?
Well , see ,
a maple 's sort of pointy in its corners .
But a sugar maple has a " u " .
It 's a " u " for sugar .
That 's you , sugar .
Jess ?
I think you should go back to New York for a while .
You could see your doctor .
- Lf you want . - Well , yeah ,
but where 'll we get the money ?
I 'd find it .
Where ?
Sure you would .
I just can 't take it anymore , Jess .
Why don 't you leave me then ?
- Don 't cry . - I 'm not crying .
Yes , you are . Don 't cry .
- Don 't cry . - No !
- Don 't get excited . - You think I 'm hopeless ?
- You be quiet ! - No .
- Be quiet ! - No , leave me !
- Hush ! Will you be quiet ? - Leave me !
- Will you be quiet , they 'll hear you ! - Leave me !
Who cares ?
What are you doing ?
Oh , I just thought it would be better to sleep apart tonight .
I 'll go .
I 'm not sleepy anyway .
Good night .
No !
No ! No !
- I don 't believe you . - No !
I think that the same creature
or whatever it is that killed the antique dealer killed the mole .
I know you all think I did it .
I didn 't do it . I didn 't do it .
I didn 't do it .
Hey , Jess , wait !
- Where are you going ? - To find a telephone .
- Be back for lunch ? - Long before .
I 'm alive . I 'm still alive .
Abigail never got to wear that wedding dress .
Drowned in the cove ...
I 'm here . I 'm here .
I was just looking at the picture .
It looks so much like you .
My Lord , it does .
Gee , how weird .
What 's the matter ?
Nothing , it 's just that
it does , it looks so very much like you .
It 's an old print . It could look like anybody .
No .
No , it 's ...
It 's the eyes .
You 're so warm .
I 'm sorry you 're so upset .
Jessica , come , Jessica .
My eyes , look in my eyes .
Come with me , come . Come with me .
It 's so stuffy in here .
- Come on , let 's go for a swim . - Yeah .
It 's stuffy .
I think you need to swim . You need some air .
Yeah , I just don 't want to get too near the cove , you know .
- Water kind of frightens me . - Oh , sure .
If you don 't want to swim ,
we could just lie by the water and get some sun .
Come on .
Come .
Follow me , Jessica . Follow me .
I 'll put some lotion on your back .
That 's good .
Oh , that 's good .
That 's very good , thank you .
Leave me alone , please . Please , leave me alone .
Get away from me .
I 'm sorry , I didn 't mean to hurt you .
- Are you all right ? I was just playing . - Please , that 's all right . That 's all right .
- I 'm so sorry . - Yes , thank you .
You okay ?
No , that 's all right .
Please , it 's all right , I didn 't mean to scare you .
I 'm sorry .
Jessica , Jessica .
Nobody 's here .
Jessica .
Come to me . This way , Jessica .
This way . This way , come .
Here , Jessica , here .
Follow , follow me . Follow , follow me .
No !
Jessica , Jessica .
Stay .
Stay , Jessica . Stay .
You 're home now .
Jessica .
Jessica , I 'm here .
I 'm here .
Where 's Duncan ?
Where is he now ?
He said he 'd be back before lunch .
I want you . What have you got ... I need you .
What have you got to live for ?
You want to die . Why go on ? You want to die .
I 'm still here .
I won 't go away , Jessica .
I 'll never go away .
You 'll never get better .
I 'm still here . I 'm in your blood .
I 'm in your blood .
Jessica , I 'm here .
I 'm here .
No !
What 's the matter ?
- Can you help me ? - Where you going ?
- Town . - Come on , get in .
Close the door .
Hello ?
Emily ?
Jessica ?
Hi .
I thought everybody had gone .
Not everybody .
Where 's Jessica ?
Oh , Jessica left .
What do you mean ?
I said , what do you mean ?
Don 't worry .
She just walked to town to find Duncan .
So , we 're alone .
Yeah .
Well ?
Do you like my new dress ?
My new , old dress ?
Yes , very much .
- You 've been working in the orchard ? - Yeah .
Where are you going ?
I should really wash this stuff off .
- Should you really ? - Yeah .
Is something wrong ?
You .
I see what you 've been doing with my friend .
I thought you liked me .
You know I do .
Do you like me now ?
Yes .
Show me .
Here we are , little lady .
- Thanks . - Take care of yourself .
Have you seen the man ... The driver of the hearse ?
No .
But you must have . It 's parked right here .
No , I didn 't .
The girl that led me to the body ,
she was warning me . She was warning me .
Jessie !
Honey , honey , no .
It 's all right .
- You 'll be okay now . - I 'm sorry .
It 'll be okay now , Jess .
I 'll take you home .
Come on .
What happened ?
Oh ! Great .
Hurry up , it 's cold .
It 's not real , Jessica . It 's not real .
It 's not real . It 's all in your mind .
It 's in your mind . Duncan 's mine . Your mind . You 're home now .
You 're home . Duncan is mine now . You 're home now .
You 're home now . He 's mine now .
No !
Woody ! Woody !
Woody !
The ferry isn 't running for you .
I sit here and I can 't believe that it happened .
And yet I have to believe it .
Nightmares or dreams .
Madness or sanity ,
I don 't know which is which .